<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="hough_predictor.png" type="Predictor">
	<name>Hough Forest Predictor</name>

	<shortDescription>Predicts detected objects according to an aggregation
		of the predictions of the individual trees in a Hough forest model.</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Predicts the location of objects in images according to an
			aggregation of the predictions of the individual trees in a Hough
			forest model.
			<br />
			Hough forests has been proposed in
			<i>Class-Specific Hough Forests for Object Detection</i>
			by Juergen Gall and Victor Lempitsky. A Hough forest can be used for
			object detection in images and is a special kind of random forest
			using a
			generalized form of a Hough transform to give probabilistic
			votes for the location of the searched objects.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Input">
			<option name="Image column">
				Select the image column to predict on.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Patch Extraction">
			<option name="Horizontal stride size">
				Defines the horizontal distance of the centers of
				two extracted
				neighbored
				patches. The width of the patches is defined in the model.
				Number of patches in horizontal direction will be
				<i>1 + (image_width - patch_width) / stride_hor</i>
				.
			</option>
			<option name="Vertical stride size">
				Defines the vertical distance of the centers of
				two extracted
				neighbored
				patches. The height of the patches is defined in the
				model.
				Number of patches in vertical direction will be
				<i>1 + (image_height - patch_height) / stride_ver</i>
				.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Voting">
			<option name="Scale 1-4">
				Prediction can be done using up to four scales
				for the images. A voting will be performed for every scaled image.
				The resulting images containing the votes will be stacked.
			</option>
			<option name="Sigma">
				Defines the sigma of the gaussian filter which is
				applied onto the votes. It will be only applied to the x and y
				direction, but not into z direction (size of the z dimension is
				defined by the number of used scales).
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Detection">
			<option name="Detect multiple objects">
				Select, if multiple objects should be detected,
				i.e. multiple maxima
				in the votes image.
				<br />
				If selected, a threshold
				needs to be defined. All local maxima having
				a value greater or
				equal the threshold value will define the center
				of a detected
				object.
				<br />
				If not
				selected, only
				one object will
				be detected which
				center
				location
				is defined
				by the global maximum.
			</option>
			<option name="Threshold">
				The threshold used to threshold the local maxima.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Back Projection">
			<option name="Size of the area around found maxima">
				Defines the span in x and y direction of a area
				around the found maxima. All patches which voted inside this area,
				will belong to the detected object.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Output">
			<option name="Votes">
				If selected, the image containing the votes will
				be appended to the output.
			</option>
			<option name="Maxima">
				If selected, the (thresholded) image containing
				the maxima defining
				the centers of the objects will be appended to
				the
				output.
			</option>
			<option name="Extended prediction labeling">
				This option is more advanced and can be used to interpret results
				and optimize parameters.
				<br />
				If selected, besides the bounding box of the
				detected objects the
				predicted labeling will contain also:
				<ul>
					<li>labels defining the (defined above) area around found maxima
						used for back projection and
					</li>
					<li>labels defining the center of the patches which has voted
						inside these areas and are spanning the bounding box.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
		</tab>

	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Hough Forest Model">
			The Hough forest model.
		</inPort>

		<inPort index="1" name="Input data">
			Input table containig an image column on
			which the prediction is
			performed.
		</inPort>

		<outPort index="0" name="Prediction output">
			A labeling will be in the output
			containing the predicted bounding
			boxes and, if the user has selected,
			an image with the collected
			votes and an image with the found maxima
			which are the centers of the
			detected objects.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view name="Image Viewer" index="0">
			Displays the selected cells with
			their associated viewer if it exists.
		</view>
		<view name="Segmentation Viewer" index="1">
			Displays the input image
			with
			the predicted segment overlays.
		</view>

	</views>
</knimeNode>
