<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="hough_learner.png" type="Learner">
	<name>Hough Forest Learner</name>

	<shortDescription>Learns a Hough forest used for object detection.</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Learns a Hough forest as proposed in
			<i>Class-Specific Hough Forests for Object Detection</i>
			by Juergen Gall and Victor Lempitsky.
			<br />
			A Hough forest can be used for
			object detection in images and is a
			special kind of random forest
			using a
			generalized form of a Hough
			transform to give probabilistic
			votes for the location of the searched
			objects.
		</intro>

		<tab name="Input">
			<option name="Image column">
				Select the image column. Can be either 2D
				(grayscale) or 3D (color).
			</option>
			<option name="Label	 column">
				Select the label column. The size of the first
				two label dimensions must be the same as the size of the image. The
				value of the labels
				do
				not care, every labeled part of the image will
				be interpreted as
				positive class, every non-labeled as negative.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Tree Options">
			<option name="Size of sample per tree">
				The size of sample used to train each tree. A
				sample contains training objects which are patches of the images
				with a corresponding label and offset. They will be randomly sampled
				from all available training objects for each tree.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of split functions">
				The number of randomly generated split functions
				used to learn each split.
			</option>
			<option name="Max. threshold of split functions">
				The maximum threshold used to generate split
				functions. Threshold will be uniformly distributed in the range of 0
				and the selected value.
			</option>
			<option name="Max. tree depth">
				Learning of a tree will stop at the selected
				depth.
			</option>
			<option name="Min. size of sample">
				Learning of a tree will stop, if the sample is
				smaller or equal the selected size.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Forest Options">
			<option name="Number of trees">
				The number of trees to learn.
			</option>
			<option name="Use static random seed">
				Select to use a seed and be able to reproduce the
				learning.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Feature Selection">
			<option name="Convert from RGB to Lab color space, if possible">
				If selected the input images will be converted to
				the Lab color space. Works only for 3D input images. If selected and
				the input are 2D images, nothing will be done.
			</option>
			<option name="Add first derivatives">
				Select to add the first derivative in x and y
				direction to the feature descriptor. Two feature channels will be
				added.
			</option>
			<option name="Use absolute value for first derivatives">
				Select to use only absolute values for the first
				derivatives.
			</option>
			<option name="Add second derivatives">
				Select to add the second derivative in x and y
				direction to the feature descriptor. Two feature channels will be
				added.
			</option>
			<option name="Use absolute value for second derivatives">
				Select to use only absolute values for the second
				derivatives.
			</option>
			<option name="Add histogram of oriented gradients">
				Select to add a histogram of oriented gradients
				to the feature descriptor. For every bin a feature channel will be
				added.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of bins">
				Select the number of bins which is the number of
				feature channels which will be added to the feature descriptor.
			</option>
			<option name="Apply a min and max filter (doubles the features)">
				A minimum and maximum filter will be applied to
				the whole
				feature descriptor. Note that this operation doubles the
				number of
				features.
			</option>
			<option name="Use only absolute values">
				Select to use only absolute values in all feature
				channels.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Patch Extraction">
			<option name="Patch width">
				The width of the patches which will be extracted
				of the images.
			</option>
			<option name="Patch height">
				The height of the patches which will be extracted
				of the images.
			</option>
			<option name="Horizontal stride size">
				Defines the horizontal distance of the centers of
				two extracted
				neighbored
				patches. Number of patches in horizontal direction will be
				<i>1 + (image_width - patch_width) / stride_hor</i>
				.
			</option>
			<option name="Vertical stride size">
				Defines the vertical distance of the centers of
				two extracted
				neighbored
				patches. Number of patches in vertical direction will be
				<i>1 + (image_height - patch_height) / stride_ver</i>
				.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input Data">
			Input table used for learning. The table
			must contain an image column and
			label column which have the same size
			in the first two dimensions.
		</inPort>

		<outPort index="0" name="Hough Forest Model">
			The learned hough forest model.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
